<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Dungeon Helper</string>

    <string name="races_activity_label">Races</string>
    <string name="equipment_activity_label">Equipment</string>
    <string name="armor_activity_label">Armor</string>

    <string name="string_races">Races</string>
    <string name="string_classes">Classes</string>
    <string name="string_equipment">Equipment</string>
    <string name="string_weapons">Weapons</string>
    <string name="string_armor">Armor</string>
    <string name="string_dice">Dice Roller</string>
    <string name="string_character_sheet">Character Creator</string>
    <string name="barbarian_header">Barbarian</string>
    <string name="barbarian_description">Primal Instinct:\n
People of towns and cities take pride in how their
civilized ways set them apart from animals, as if
denying one’s own nature was a mark of superiority. To
a barbarian, though, civilization is no virtue, but a sign
of weakness. The strong embrace their animal nature keen
instincts, primal physicality, and ferocious rage.
Barbarians are uncomfortable when hedged in by walls
and crowds. They thrive in the wilds of their homelands:
the tundra, jungle, or grasslands w here their tribes
live and hunt.
Barbarians come alive in the chaos of combat.
They can enter a berserk state where rage takes over,
giving them superhuman strength and resilience. A
barbarian can draw on this reservoir of fury only a few
times without resting, but those few rages are usually
sufficient to defeat whatever threats arise.\n\n
A Life of Danger:\n
Not every member of the tribes deemed “barbarians”
by scions of civilized society has the barbarian class. A
true barbarian among these people is as uncommon as
a skilled fighter in a town, and he or she plays a similar
role as a protector of the people and a leader in times
of war. Life in the wild places of the world is fraught
with peril: rival tribes, deadly weather, and terrifying
monsters. Barbarians charge headlong into that danger
so that their people don’t have to.
Their courage in the face of danger makes barbarians
perfectly suited for adventuring. Wandering is often a
way of life for their native tribes, and the rootless life of
the adventurer is little hardship for a barbarian. Some
barbarians m iss the close-knit family structures of the
tribe, but eventually find them replaced by the bonds
formed among the members of their adventuring parties.
</string>
    <string name="bard_header">Bard</string>
    <string name="bard_description">Music And Magic:\n In the worlds of D&amp;D, words and music are
not just vibrations of air, but vocalizations with
power all their own. The bard is a master of song,
speech, and the magic they contain. Bards say
that the multiverse was spoken into existence, that the
words o f the gods gave it shape, and that echoes of these
primordial Words of Creation still resound throughout
the cosmos. The music of bards is an attempt to snatch
and harness those echoes, subtly woven into their
spells and powers.
The greatest strength of bards is their sheer
versatility. Many bards prefer to stick to the sidelines
in combat, using their magic to inspire their allies and
hinder their foes from a distance. But bards are capable
of defending themselves in melee if necessary, using
their magic to bolster their sw ords and armor. Their
spells lean toward charm s and illusions rather than
blatantly destructive spells. They have a wide-ranging
knowledge of many subjects and a natural aptitude
that lets them do alm ost anything well. Bards become
masters of the talents they set their minds to perfecting,
from musical perform ance to esoteric knowledge.\n\n
Learning from Experience:\n
True bards are not com m on in the world. Not every
minstrel singing in a tavern or jester cavorting in a royal
court is a bard. Discovering the magic hidden in music
requires hard study and som e measure of natural talent
that most troubadours and jongleurs lack. It can be hard
to spot the difference between these perform ers and true
bards, though. A bard’s life is spent wandering across
the land gathering lore, telling stories, and living on the
gratitude of audiences, much like any other entertainer.
But a depth of knowledge, a level of musical skill, and a
touch of magic set bards apart from their fellows.
Only rarely do bards settle in one place for long, and
their natural desire to travel—to find new tales to tell,
new skills to learn, and new discoveries beyond the
horizon—makes an adventuring career a natural calling.
Every adventure is an opportunity to learn, practice a
variety of skills, enter long-forgotten tombs, discover lost
works of magic, decipher old tomes, travel to strange
places, or encounter exotic creatures. Bards love to
accompany heroes to witness their deeds firsthand. A
bard who can tell an awe-inspiring story from personal
experience earns renown among other bards. Indeed,
after telling so many stories about heroes accomplishing
mighty deeds, many bards take these themes to heart
and assume heroic roles themselves</string>
    <string name="cleric_header">Cleric</string>
    <string name="cleric_description">Healers and Warriors\n
Divine magic, as the name suggests, is the power of
the gods, flowing from them into the world. Clerics are
conduits for that power, manifesting it as miraculous
effects. The gods don’t grant this power to everyone who
seeks it, but only to those chosen to fulfill a high calling.
Harnessing divine magic doesn’t rely on study or
training. A cleric might learn formulaic prayers and
ancient rites, but the ability to cast cleric spells relies on
devotion and an intuitive sense o f a deity’s wishes.
Clerics combine the helpful magic of healing and
inspiring their allies with spells that harm and hinder
foes. They can provoke awe and dread, lay curses of
plague or poison, and even call down flames from heaven
to consume their enemies. For those evildoers who will
benefit most from a mace to the head, clerics depend on
their combat training to let them wade into melee with
the power of the gods on their side.\n\n
Divine Agents:\n
Not every acolyte or officiant at a temple or shrine is a
cleric. Some priests are called to a simple life of temple
service, carrying out their gods’ will through prayer and
sacrifice, not by magic and strength of arms. In some
cities, priesthood amounts to a political office, viewed
as a stepping stone to higher positions of authority and
involving no communion with a god at all. True clerics
are rare in most hierarchies.
When a cleric takes up an adventuring life, it is usually
because his or her god demands it. Pursuing the goals
of the gods often involves braving dangers beyond the
walls of civilization, smiting evil or seeking holy relics in
ancient tombs. Many clerics are also expected to protect their deities’ worshipers, which can mean fighting
rampaging orc s, negotiating peace between warring
nations, or sealing a portal that would allow a demon
prince to enter the world.
Most adventuring clerics maintain some connection to
established temples and orders of their faiths. A temple
might ask for a cleric’s aid, or a high priest might be in a
position to demand it.</string>
    <string name="druid_header">Druid</string>
    <string name="druid_description">Power of Nature:\n
Druids revere nature above all, gaining their spells and
other magical powers either from the force of nature
itself or from a nature deity. Many druids pursue a
mystic spirituality of transcendent union with nature
rather than devotion to a divine entity, while others
serve gods o f wild nature, animals, or elemental forces.
The ancient druidic traditions are sometimes called
the Old Faith, in contrast to the worship of gods in
temples and shrines.
Druid spells are oriented toward nature and anim als—
the power of tooth and claw, of sun and moon, of fire
and storm. Druids also gain the ability to take on animal
forms, and some druids make a particular study of this
practice, even to the point where they prefer animal
form to their natural form.\n\n
Preserve the Balance:\n
For druids, nature exists in a precarious balance. The
four elements that make up a world—air, earth, fire, and water—must remain in equilibrium. If one element
were to gain power over the others, the world could be
destroyed, drawn into one of the elemental planes and
broken apart into its component elements. Thus, druids
oppose cults of Elemental Evil and others who promote
one element to the exclusion of others.
Druids are also concerned with the delicate ecological
balance that sustains plant and animal life, and the need
for civilized folk to live in harmony with nature, not in
opposition to it. Druids accept that w hich is cruel in
nature, and they hate that which is unnatural, including
aberrations (such as beholders and mind flayers)
and undead (such as zom bies and vampires). Druids
sometim es lead raids against such creatures, especially
when the monsters encroach on the druids’ territory.
Druids are often found guarding sacred sites or
watching over regions of unspoiled nature. But when a
significant danger arises, threatening nature’s balance
or the lands they protect, druids take on a more active
role in combating the threat, as adventurers.
</string>
    <string name="fighter_header">Fighter</string>
    <string name="fighter_description">
Well-Rounded Specialists:\n
Fighters learn the basics of all combat styles. Every
fighter can swing an axe, fence with a rapier, wield a
longsword or a greatsword, use a bow, and even trap foes
in a net with some degree of skill. Likewise, a fighter is
adept with shields and every form of armor. Beyond that
basic degree of familiarity, each fighter specializes in a
certain style of combat. Som e concentrate on archery,
some on fighting with two weapons at once, and some
on augmenting their martial skills with magic. This
combination of broad general ability and extensive
specialization makes fighters superior combatants
on battlefields and in dungeons alike.\n\n
Trained for Danger:\n
Not every member of the city watch, the village militia,
or the queen’s army is a fighter. Most of these troops are
relatively untrained soldiers with only the most basic
combat knowledge. Veteran soldiers, military officers,
trained bodyguards, dedicated knights, and similar
figures are fighters. Some fighters feel drawn to use their training as
adventurers. The dungeon delving, monster slaying, and
other dangerous work common among adventurers is
second nature for a fighter, not all that different from
the life he or she left behind. There are greater risks,
perhaps, but also much greater rewards—few fighters in
the city watch have the opportunity to discover a magic
flame tongue sword, for example.</string>
    <string name="monk_header">Monk</string>
    <string name="monk_description">The Magic of Ki:\n
Monks make careful study of a magical energy that most
monastic traditions call ki. This energy is an element
of the magic that suffuses the multiverse—specifically,
the element that flows through living bodies. Monks
harness this power within themselves to create magical
effects and exceed their bodies\' physical capabilities,
and some of their special attacks can hinder the flow of
ki in their opponents. Using this energy, monks channel
uncanny speed and strength into their unarmed strikes.
As they gain experience, their martial training and their
mastery of ki gives them more power over their bodies
and the bodies of their foes.\n\n
Training and Asceticism:\n
Small walled cloisters dot the landscapes of the worlds
of D&amp;D, tiny refuges from the flow of ordinary life,
where time seems to stand still. The monks who live
there seek personal perfection through contemplation
and rigorous training. Many entered the monastery
as children, sent to live there when their parents died,
when food couldn’t be found to support them, or in
return for some kindness that the monks had performed
for their families.
Some monks live entirely apart from the surrounding
population, secluded from anything that might impede
their spiritual progress. Others are sworn to isolation, emerging only to serve as spies or assassins at the
command of their leader, a noble patron, or some other
mortal or divine power.
The majority of monks don’t shun their neighbors,
making frequent visits to nearby towns or villages and
exchanging their service for food and other goods. As
versatile warriors, monks often end up protecting their
neighbors from monsters or tyrants.
For a monk, becoming an adventurer means leaving
a structured, communal lifestyle to become a wanderer.
This can be a harsh transition, and monks don’t
undertake it lightly. Those who leave their cloisters take
their work seriously, approaching their adventures as
personal tests of their physical and spiritual growth.
As a rule, monks care little for material wealth and are
driven by a desire to accomplish a greater mission than
merely slaying monsters and plundering their treasure.</string>
    <string name="paladin_header">Paladin</string>
    <string name="paladin_description">The Cause of Righteousness:\n
A paladin swears to uphold justice and righteousness,
to stand with the good things of the world against the
encroaching darkness, and to hunt the forces of evil
wherever they lurk. Different paladins focus on various
aspects of the cause of righteousness, but all are
bound by the oaths that grant them power to do their
sacred work. Although many paladins are devoted to
gods of good, a paladin’s power com es as much from a
commitment to justice itself as it does from a god.
Paladins train for years to learn the skills of combat,
mastering a variety of weapons and armor. Even so,
their martial skills are secondary to the magical power
they wield: power to heal the sick and injured, to smite
the wicked and the undead, and to protect the innocent
and those who join them in the fight for justice.\n\n
Beyond the Mundane Life:\n
Almost by definition, the life of a paladin is an
adventuring life. Unless a lasting injury has taken him
or her away from adventuring for a time, every paladin
lives on the front lines of the cosmic struggle against evil. Fighters are rare enough am ong the ranks of the
militias and armies of the world, but even fewer people
can claim the true calling of a paladin. When they do
receive the call, these warriors turn from their former
occupations and take up arms to fight evil. Sometimes
their oaths lead them into the service of the crown as
leaders of elite groups of knights, but even then their
loyalty is first to the cause of righteousness, not to
crown and country.
Adventuring paladins take their work seriously. A
delve into an ancient ruin or dusty crypt can be a quest
driven by a higher purpose than the acquisition of
treasure. Evil lurks in dungeons and primeval forests,
and even the smallest victory against it can tilt the
cosmic balance away from oblivion.</string>
    <string name="ranger_header">Ranger</string>
    <string name="ranger_description">Deadly Hunters:\n
Warriors of the wilderness, rangers specialize in
hunting the monsters that threaten the edges of
civilization—humanoid raiders, rampaging beasts and
monstrosities, terrible giants, and deadly dragons. They
learn to track their quarry as a predator does, moving
stealthily through the wilds and hiding themselves in
brush and rubble. Rangers focus their combat training
on techniques that are particularly useful against their
specific favored foes.
Thanks to their familiarity with the wilds, rangers
acquire the ability to cast spells that harness nature’s
power, much as a druid does. Their spells, like their
combat abilities, emphasize speed, stealth, and the hunt.
A ranger’s talents and abilities are honed with deadly
focus on the grim task of protecting the borderlands.\n\n
Independent Adventurers:\n
Though a ranger might make a living as a hunter, a
guide, or a tracker, a ranger’s true calling is to defend
the outskirts of civilization from the ravages of monsters
and humanoid hordes that press in from the wild. In
some places, rangers gather in secretive orders or join
forces with druidic circles. Many rangers, though, are
independent almost to a fault, knowing that, when a
dragon or a band of orcs attacks, a ranger might be the
first—and possibly the last—line of defense.
This fierce independence makes rangers w ell suited
to adventuring, since they are accustomed to life far
from the comforts of a dry bed and a hot bath. Faced
with city-bred adventurers who grouse and whine about
the hardships of the wild, rangers respond with some mixture of amusement, frustration, and compassion.
But they quickly learn that other adventurers who can
carry their own weight in a fight against civilization’s
foes are worth any extra burden. Coddled city folk might
not know how to feed themselves or find fresh water in
the wild, but they make up for it in other ways.
</string>
    <string name="rogue_header">Rogue</string>
    <string name="rogue_description">Skill And Precision:\n
        Rogues devote as much effort to mastering the use of
a variety of skills as they do to perfecting their combat
abilities, giving them a broad expertise that few other
characters can match. Many rogues focus on stealth and
deception, while others refine the skills that help them
in a dungeon environment, such as climbing, finding and
disarming traps, and opening locks.
When it com es to combat, rogues prioritize cunning
over brute strength. A rogue would rather make one
precise strike, placing it exactly where the attack will
hurt the target most, than wear an opponent down
with a barrage of attacks. Rogues have an almost
supernatural knack for avoiding danger, and a few learn
magical tricks to supplement their other abilities.\n\n
A Shady Living:\n
Every town and city has its share of rogues. Most of
them live up to the worst stereotypes of the class,
making a living as burglars, assassins, cutpurses, and
con artists. Often, these scoundrels are organized
into thieves’ guilds or crim e families. Plenty of rogues
operate independently, but even they sometimes
recruit apprentices to help them in their scams
and heists. A few rogues make an honest living as locksmiths, investigators, or exterminators, which can
be a dangerous job in a world where dire rats—and
wererats—haunt the sewers.
As adventurers, rogues fall on both sides of the law.
Some are hardened criminals who decide to seek
their fortune in treasure hoards, while others take up
a life of adventure to escape from the law. Some have
learned and perfected their skills with the explicit
purpose of infiltrating ancient ruins and hidden crypts
in search of treasure.</string>
    <string name="sorcerer_header">Rogue</string>
    <string name="sorcerer_description">Raw Magic:\n
        Magic is a part of every sorcerer, suffusing body, mind,
and spirit with a latent power that waits to be tapped.
Some sorcerers wield magic that springs from an
ancient bloodline infused with the magic of dragons.
Others carry a raw, uncontrolled magic within them,
a chaotic storm that manifests in unexpected ways.
The appearance of sorcerous pow ers is wildly
unpredictable. Some draconic bloodlines produce
exactly one sorcerer in every generation, but in other
lines of descent every individual is a sorcerer. Most
of the time, the talents of sorcery appear as apparent
flukes. Some sorcerers can’t name the origin of their
power, while others trace it to strange events in their
own lives. The touch of a demon, the blessing of a
dryad at a baby’s birth, or a taste of the water from
a mysterious spring might spark the gift of sorcery.
So too might the gift of a deity of m agic, exposure
to the elemental forces of the Inner Planes or the
maddening chaos of Limbo, or a glimpse into the
inner workings of reality.
Sorcerers have no use for the spellbooks and ancient
tom es of m agic lore that wizards rely on, nor do they
rely on a patron to grant their spells as warlocks do.
By learning to harness and channel their own inborn
magic, they can discover new and staggering ways
to unleash that power.\n\n
Unexplained Powers:\n
Sorcerers are rare in the world, and it’s unusual to find
a sorcerer who is not involved in the adventuring life
in some way. People with magical power seething in
their veins soon discover that the power doesn’t like to
stay quiet. A sorcerer’s magic wants to be wielded, and
it has a tendency to spill out in unpredictable ways if
it isn’t called on. Sorcerers often
have obscure or quixotic
motivations driving them
to adventure. Som e seek a greater
understanding of the magical force that infuses
them, or the answer to the mystery of its origin. Others
hope to find a way to get rid of it, or to unleash its full
potential. Whatever their goals, sorcerers are every bit
as useful to an adventuring party as wizards, making
up for a comparative lack of breadth in their magical
knowledge with enormous flexibility in using the
spells they know.</string>
    <string name="warlock_header">Warlock</string>
    <string name="warlock_description">Sworn and Beholden:\n
A warlock is defined by a pact with an otherworldly
being. Sometimes the relationship between warlock
and patron is like that of a cleric and a deity, though
the beings that serve as patrons for warlocks are not
gods. A warlock might lead a cult dedicated to a demon
prince, an archdevil, or an utterly alien entity—beings
not typically served by clerics. More often, though, the
arrangement is similar to that between a master and
an apprentice. The warlock learns and grows in power,
at the cost of occasional services performed on the
patron’s behalf.
The magic bestowed on a warlock ranges from minor
but lasting alterations to the warlock\'s being (such as
the ability to see in darkness or to read any language)
to access to powerful spells. Unlike bookish wizards,
warlocks supplement their magic with some facility
at hand-to-hand combat. They are com fortable in light
arm or and know how to use simple weapons.\n\n
Delvers in to Secrets:\n
Warlocks are driven by an insatiable need for knowledge
and power, which compels them into their pacts and
shapes their lives. This thirst drives warlocks into their
pacts and shapes their later careers as well.
Stories of warlocks binding themselves to fiends are
widely known. But many warlocks serve patrons that
are not fiendish. Sometim es a traveler in the wilds
comes to a strangely beautiful tower, meets its fey lord
or lady, and stumbles into a pact without being fully
aware of it. And sometim es, while poring over tomes of forbidden lore, a brilliant but crazed student’s mind is
opened to realities beyond the material world and to the
alien beings that dwell in the outer void.
Once a pact is made, a warlock’s thirst for knowledge
and power can’t be slaked with mere study and research.
No one makes a pact with such a mighty patron if he or
she doesn’t intend to use the power thus gained. Rather,
the vast majority of warlocks spend their days in active
pursuit of their goals, which typically means some kind
of adventuring. Furthermore, the demands of their
patrons drive warlocks toward adventure.
</string>
    <string name="wizard_header">Wizard</string>
    <string name="wizard_description">Scholars of the Arcane:\n
Wild and enigmatic, varied in form and function, the
power of magic draws students who seek to master
its mysteries. Some aspire to become like the gods,
shaping reality itself. Though the casting of a typical
spell requires merely the utterance of a few strange
words, fleeting gestures, and sometimes a pinch or
clump of exotic materials, these surface components
barely hint at the expertise attained after years of
apprenticeship and countless hours of study.
Wizards live and die by their spells. Everything else
is secondary. They learn new spells as they experiment
and grow in experience. They can also learn them from
other wizards, from ancient tomes or inscriptions,
and from ancient creatures (such as the fey) that are
steeped in magic.\n\n
    The Lure of Knowledge:\n
Wizards’ lives are seldom mundane. The closest a
wizard is likely to come to an ordinary life is working
as a sage or lecturer in a library or university, teaching
others the secrets of the multiverse. Other wizards sell
their services as diviners, serve in military forces, or
pursue lives of crime or domination.
But the lure of knowledge and power calls even the
most unadventurous wizards out of the safety of their
libraries and laboratories and into crumbling ruins and
lost cities. Most wizards believe that their counterparts
in ancient civilizations knew secrets of magic that have
been lost to the ages, and discovering those secrets
could unlock the path to a power greater than any magic
available in the present age.
</string>
    <string name="dwarf_header">Dwarf</string>
    <string name="dwarf_quote">\"Yerlate, elf!\" came the rough edge of a familiar voice.
        Bruenor Battlehammer walked up the back of his
        dead foe, disregarding the fact that the heavy monster lay
        on top of his elven friend. In spite of the added discomfort,
        the dwarf\’s long, pointed, often-broken nose and graystreaked
        though still-fiery red beard came as a welcome
        sight to Drizzt. \"Knew I’d find ye in trouble if I came out
        an\' looked for ye!\"\n\n

        —R. A . Salvatore, The Crystal Shard</string>
    <string name="dwarf_description">Your dwarf character has an assortment of inborn
        abilities, part and parcel of dwarven nature.\n\n

        Ability Score Increase: Your Constitution score increases by 2.\n\n

        Age: Dwarves mature at the same rate as humans, but they’re considered young until they
        reach the age of 50. On average, they live about 350 years.\n\n

        Alignment: Most dwarves are lawful, believing firmly in the benefits of a well-ordered
        society. They tend toward good as well, with a strong sense of fair play and
        a belief that everyone deserves to share in the benefits of
        a just order.\n\n

        Size: Dwarves stand between 4 and 5 feet tall and
        average about 150 pounds. Your size is Medium.\n\n

        Speed: Your base walking speed is 25 feet. Your
        speed is not reduced by wearing heavy armor.\n\n

        Dark-vision: Accustomed to life underground, you
        have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You
        can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were
        bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You
        can’t discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.\n\n

        Dwarven Resilience: You have advantage on saving
        throws against poison, and you have resistance against
        poison damage (explained in chapter 9).\n\n

        Dwarven Combat Training: You have proficiency
        with the battleaxe, handaxe, throwing hammer,
        and warhammer.\n\n

        Tool Proficiency: You gain proficiency with the
        artisan’s tools of your choice: smith’s tools, brewer’s
        supplies, or mason’s tools.\n\n

        Stonecunning: Whenever you make an Intelligence
        (History) check related to the origin of stonework, you
        are considered proficient in the History skill and add
        double your proficiency bonus to the check, instead of
        your normal proficiency bonus.\n\n

        Languages: You can speak, read, and write Common
        and Dwarvish. Dwarvish is full of hard consonants and
        guttural sounds, and those characteristics spill over into
        whatever other language a dwarf might speak.</string>

    <string name="elf_header">Elf</string>
    <string name="elf_quote">\"I have never imagined such beauty existed,\"
        Goldmoon said softly. The day\'s march had been difficult, but the reward at the end was
        beyond their dreams. The companions stood on the high cliff over the fabled city of
        Qualinost. Four slender spires rose from the city’s corners like glistening
        spindles, their brilliant white stone marbled with shining
        silver. Graceful arches, swooping from spire to spire, soared
        through the air. Crafted by ancient dwarven metalsmiths,
        they were strong enough to hold the weight of an army, yet
        they appeared so delicate that a bird lighting on them might
        overthrow the balance. These glistening arches were the
        city\’s only boundaries; there was no wall around Qualinost.
        The elven city opened its arms lovingly to the wilderness.\n\n

        —Margaret Weis and Tracy Hickman,\n
        Dragons of Autumn Twilight</string>
    <string name="elf_description">Your elf character has a variety of natural abilities, the
        result of thousands of years of elven refinement.\n\n

        Ability Score Increase: Your Dexterity score
        increases by 2.\n\n

        Age: Although elves reach physical maturity at about
        the same age as humans, the elven understanding of
        adulthood goes beyond physical growth to encompass
        worldly experience. An elf typically claims adulthood
        and an adult name around the age of 100 and can live
        to be 750 years old.\n\n

        Alignment: Elves love freedom, variety, and self expression,
        so they lean strongly toward the gentler
        aspects of chaos. They value and protect others\'
        freedom as well as their own, and they are more
        often good than not. The drow are an exception; their
        exile into the Underdark has made them vicious and
        dangerous. Drow are more often evil than not.\n\n

        Size: Elves range from under 5 to over 6 feet tall and
        have slender builds. Your size is Medium.\n\n

        Speed: Your base walking speed is 30 feet.\n\n

        Darkvision: Accustom ed to twilit forests and the night
        sky, you have superior vision in dark and dim conditions.
        You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it
        were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light.
        You can’t discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.\n\n

        Keen Senses: You have proficiency in the
        Perception skill.\n\n

        Fey Ancestry: You have advantage on saving throws
        against being charmed, and magic can\’t put you to sleep.\n\n

        Trance: Elves don’t need to sleep. Instead, they
        meditate deeply, remaining semiconscious, for 4
        hours a day. (The Common word for such meditation
        is \“trance.\”) While meditating, you can dream after a
        fashion; such dreams are actually mental exercises that
        have become reflexive through years of practice. After
        resting in this way, you gain the same benefit that a
        human does from 8 hours of sleep.\n\n

        Languages: You can speak, read, and write Common
        and Elvish. Elvish is fluid, with subtle intonations and
        intricate grammar. Elven literature is rich and varied,
        and their songs and poems are famous among other
        races. Many bards learn their language so they can add
        Elvish ballads to their repertoires.</string>

    <string name="halfling_header">Halfling</string>
    <string name="halfling_quote">Regis the halfling, the only one of his kind for
        hundreds of miles in any direction, locked his fingers behind
        his head and leaned back against the mossy blanket
        of the tree trunk. Regis was short, even by the standards
        of his diminutive race, with the fluff of his curly brown
        locks barely cresting the three-foot mark, but his belly was
        amply thickened by his love of a good meal, or several, as
        the opportunities presented themselves. The crooked stick
        that served as his fishing pole rose up above him, clenched
        between two of his toes, and hung out over the quiet lake,
        mirrored perfectly in the glassy surface of Maer Dualdon.\n\n

        —R.A. Salvatore, The Crystal Shard</string>
    <string name="halfling_description">Your halfling character has a number of traits in
        common with all other halflings.\n\n

        Ability Score Increase: Your Dexterity score
        increases by 2.\n\n

        Age: A halfling reaches adulthood at the age of
        20 and generally lives into the middle of his or her
        second century.\n\n

        Alignment: Most halflings are lawful good. As a rule,
        they are good-hearted and kind, hate to see others in
        pain, and have no tolerance for oppression. They are
        also very orderly and traditional, leaning heavily on
        the support of their community and the comfort of
        their old ways.\n\n

        Size: Halflings average about 3 feet tall and weigh
        about 40 pounds. Your size is Small.\n\n

        Speed: Your base walking speed is 25 feet.\n\n

        Lucky: When you roll a 1 on an attack roll, ability
        check, or saving throw, you can reroll the die and must
        use the new roll.\n\n

        Brave: You have advantage on saving throws against
        being frightened.\n\n

        Halfling Nimbleness: You can move through the
        space of any creature that is of a size larger than yours.\n\n

        Languages: You can speak, read, and write Common
        and Halfling. The Halfling language isn’t secret, but
        halflings are loath to share it with others. They write
        very little, so they don’t have a rich body of literature.
        Their oral tradition, however, is very strong. Almost all
        halflings speak Common to converse with the people
        in whose lands they dwell or through which they
        are traveling.</string>

    <string name="human_header">Human</string>
    <string name="human_quote">These were the stories of a restless people who
        long ago took to the seas and rivers in longboats, first to
        pillage and terrorize, then to settle. Yet there was an energy,
        a love of adventure, that sang from every page. Long into
        the night Uriel read, lighting candle after precious candle.
        She\'d never given much thought to humans, but these
        stories fascinated her. In these yellowed pages were tales of
        bold heroes, strange and fierce animals, mighty primitive gods,
        and a magic that was part and fabric of that distant land.\n\n

        —Elaine Cunningham , Daughter of the Drow</string>
    <string name="human_description">It\’s hard to make generalizations about humans, but
        your human character has these traits.\n\n

        Ability Score Increase: Your ability scores each
        increase by 1.\n\n

        Age: Humans reach adulthood in their late teens and
        live less than a century.\n\n

        Alignment: Humans tend toward no
        particular alignment. The best and the worst are
        found am ong them.\n\n

        Size: Humans vary widely in height and build, from
        barely 5 feet to well over 6 feet tall. Regardless of your
        position in that range, your size is Medium.\n\n

        Speed: Your base walking speed is 30 feet.\n\n

        Languages: You can speak, read, and write Common
        and one extra language of your choice. Humans typically
        learn the languages of other peoples they deal with,
        including obscure dialects. They are fond of sprinkling
        their speech with words borrowed from other tongues:
        Orc curses, Elvish musical expressions, Dwarvish
        military phrases, and so on.</string>

    <string name="dragonborn_header">Dragonborn</string>
    <string name="dragonborn_quote">Her father stood on the first of the three stairs
        that led down from the portal, unmoving. The scales of his
        face had grown paler around the edges, but Clanless Mehen
        still looked as if he could wrestle down a dire bear himself.
        His familiar well-worn armor was gone, replaced by
        violet-tinted scale armor with bright silvery tracings. There
        was a blazon on his arm as well, the mark of some foreign
        house. The sword at his back was the same, though, the one
        he had carried since even before he had found the twins left
        in swaddling at the gates of Arush Vayem.
        For all her life, Farideh had known that reading her
        father\’s face was a skill she\'d been fortunate to learn. A
        human who couldn\’t spot the shift of her eyes or Havilar\’s
        would certainly see only the indifference of a dragon in
        Clanless Mehen\’s face. But the shift of scales, the arch of a
        ridge, the set of his eyes, the gape of his teeth\—her father\'s
        face spoke volumes. But every scale of it, this time, seemed completely still\—
        the indifference of a dragon, even to Farideh.\n\n

        —Erin M. Evans, The Adversary
    </string>
    <string name="dragonborn_description">Your draconic heritage manifests in a variety of traits
        you share with other dragonborn.\n\n

        Ability Score Increase: Your Strength score
        increases by 2, and your Charisma score increases by 1.\n\n

        Age: Young dragonborn grow quickly. They walk
        hours after hatching, attain the size and development
        of a 10-year-old human child by the age of 3, and reach
        adulthood by 15. They live to be around 80.\n\n

        Alignment: Dragonborn tend to extremes, making a
        conscious choice for one side or the other in the cosmic
        war between good and evil (represented by Bahamut
        and Tiamat, respectively). Most dragonborn are good,
        but those who side with Tiamat can be terrible villains.\n\n

        Size: Dragonborn are taller and heavier than humans,
        standing well over 6 feet tall and averaging almost 250
        pounds. Your size is Medium.\n\n

        Speed: Your base walking speed is 30 feet.
        \n\n

        Draconic Ancestry: You have draconic ancestry.
        Choose one type of dragon from the Draconic Ancestry
        table. Your breath weapon and damage resistance are
        determined by the dragon type, as shown in the table below.\n\n

        Black Acid - 30 ft. line (Dex. save)\n
        Blue Lightning - 30 ft. line (Dex. save)\n
        Brass Fire - 30 ft. line (Dex. save)\n
        Bronze Lightning - 30 ft. line (Dex. save)\n
        Copper Acid - 30 ft. line (Dex. save)\n
        Cold Fire - 15 ft. cone (Dex. save)\n
        Green Poison - 15 ft. cone (Con. save)\n
        Red Fire - 15 ft. cone (Dex. save)\n
        Silver Cold - 15 ft. cone (Con. save)\n
        White Cold - 15 ft. cone (Con. save)\n\n

        Breath Weapon: You can use your action to exhale
        destructive energy. Your draconic ancestry determines
        the size, shape, and damage type of the exhalation.
        W hen you use your breath weapon, each creature in
        the area of the exhalation must make a saving throw,
        the type of which is determined by your draconic
        ancestry. The DC for this saving throw equals 8 +
        your Constitution modifier + your proficiency bonus. A
        creature takes 2d6 damage on a failed save, and half
        as much damage on a successful one. The damage
        increases to 3d6 at 6th level, 4d6 at 11th level, and 5d6
        at 16th level. After you use your breath weapon, you can’t use it
        again until you complete a short or long rest.\n\n

        Damage Resistance: You have resistance to the
        damage type associated with your draconic ancestry.\n\n

        Languages: You can speak, read, and write Common
        and Draconic. Draconic is thought to be one of the
        oldest languages and is often used in the study of magic.
        The language sounds harsh to m ost other creatures and
        includes numerous hard consonants and sibilants.</string>

    <array name="Dice_Types">
        <item>"D2"</item>
        <item>D4</item>
        <item>D6</item>
        <item>D8</item>
        <item>D10</item>
        <item>D12</item>
        <item>D20</item>
        <item>Percentile</item>
    </array>

    <string name="string_char_sheet_text">Character Sheet</string>
    <string name="string_char_name_text">Character Name: </string>
    <string name="string_char_level_text">Level: </string>
    <string name="string_char_class_text">Class: </string>
    <string name="string_char_race_text">Race: </string>
    <string name="string_char_stats_text">Characters Stats: </string>
    <string name="string_char_stats_str_text">Strength: </string>
    <string name="string_char_stats_dex_text">Dexterity: </string>
    <string name="string_char_stats_con_text">Constitution: </string>
    <string name="string_char_stats_int_text">Intellect: </string>
    <string name="string_char_stats_wis_text">Wisdom: </string>
    <string name="string_char_stats_mod_text">Modifier: </string>
    <string name="string_char_button_new">New</string>
    <string name="string_char_button_save">Save</string>
    <string name="string_char_button_load">Load</string>

    <string-array name="races">
        <item>Dwarf</item>
        <item>Elf</item>
        <item>Halfling</item>
        <item>Human</item>
        <item>Dragonborn</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="classes">
        <item>Barbarian</item>
        <item>Bard</item>
        <item>Cleric</item>
        <item>Druid</item>
        <item>Fighter</item>
        <item>Monk</item>
        <item>Paladin</item>
        <item>Ranger</item>
        <item>Rogue</item>
        <item>Sorcerer</item>
        <item>Warlock</item>
        <item>Wizard</item>
    </string-array>
</resources>
